<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Meta on Just a Blog in the Park</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/tags/meta/</link><description>Recent content in Meta on Just a Blog in the Park</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href="https://github.com/Artiavis">Jeff Rabinowitz&lt;/a>, 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 20:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.justabloginthepark.com/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Turning Over a New Writing Leaf</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2021/01/18/turning-over-a-new-writing-leaf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 20:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2021/01/18/turning-over-a-new-writing-leaf/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have you ever known that you wanted to write about something, but weren&amp;rsquo;t sure where to start? I&amp;rsquo;ve often experienced that when writing for this very blog. I&amp;rsquo;ll have a topic like &lt;a href="https://www.justabloginthepark.com/tags/programming">programming&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://www.justabloginthepark.com/tags/cooking">cooking&lt;/a> that I want to share a thought about, and get stuck&amp;hellip; starting. That&amp;rsquo;s one of the reasons I haven&amp;rsquo;t been blogging as often as I&amp;rsquo;d have liked to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In order to tackle this &amp;ldquo;writer&amp;rsquo;s block&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try changing my blogging approach in three related ways: setting explicit writing goals, taking notes towards those ends, and not rushing the writing process.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Switching to Hugo Blogging</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2017/06/03/switching-to-hugo-blogging/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2017/06/03/switching-to-hugo-blogging/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently decided to switch the backend static site compilation toolchain for
this blog from the small &lt;a href="https://github.com/cryogen-project/cryogen">Cryogen project&lt;/a>
in &lt;a href="https://clojure.org/">Clojure&lt;/a> to the venerable &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo&lt;/a>
project written in &lt;a href="https://golang.org/">Golang&lt;/a>. Although I had previously
written that I wanted a hackable static site generator at
&lt;a href="https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2015/10/24/returning-to-blogging-with-cryogen/">Returning to Blogging with Cryogen&lt;/a>,
my requirements lately have changed.
I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a couple of quick notes about why I switched (and why I didn&amp;rsquo;t).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="hackabletoolchain--maintainabletoolchain">hackableToolchain &amp;lt;&amp;lt; maintainableToolchain&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>An easily hackable blog generator became less valueable to me than a robust and well
maintained one. Although it was nice getting to contribute code to Cryogen and to
make a difference, and to be able to understand the code base, the value of established
and battle-tested code is something I ignored at the time. (I knew it was a factor,
but at the time I just wanted to get rolling quickly. These days I&amp;rsquo;d rather have
something that works on its own.)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Returning to Blogging with Cryogen</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2015/10/24/returning-to-blogging-with-cryogen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2015/10/24/returning-to-blogging-with-cryogen/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a long while since I last blogged. My last post dates back to
April of 2014, shortly before I graduated from Rutgers Engineering.
My life since then has been a bit of a whirlwind. I&amp;rsquo;ve since graduated,
moved to the Upper West Side, started working in banking, gotten engaged
and married, and moved out. I suppose I could be forgiven for not blogging
as actively.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-i-took-down-my-old-blog">Why I Took Down My Old Blog&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My old blog was running on &lt;a href="ghost.org">Ghost&lt;/a>, a nifty JavaScript-based
modern reimagination of the classic web-based blogging platform. Ghost
has some gorgeous themes, a svelte editing experience, and seems poised
to be the next generation of blogging platforms. It seems great. Why
did I leave it behind?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome to the Park!</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2013/10/28/welcome-to-the-park/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2013/10/28/welcome-to-the-park/</guid><description>&lt;p>I love going for walks in the park. Whether I&amp;rsquo;m flushed with ideas and want to
let them percolate in my head, or I&amp;rsquo;m bone dry and can&amp;rsquo;t seem to get a single
thought to hit me, I find going for a walk always helps. Something about keeping
moving and watching the world stroll by always seems to get the juices flowing
at just the right pace.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But a walk can&amp;rsquo;t be just anywhere to have this effect. Walking the city streets,
for example, just doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to have the same effect. Perhaps it has to do
with the noise, or maybe it&amp;rsquo;s just the commotion of people rushing about trying
to &amp;ldquo;get things done&amp;rdquo;. Either way, I demand my meditative gardens to be slightly
removed from the most heavily trafficked paths so that I can (perhaps somewhat
selfishly) enjoy their tranquility. (For instance, the Rutgers Student Center
below might be a bit too active to get any good thinking done.)&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>