<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>meta on Just a Blog in the Park</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/tags/meta/</link><description>Recent content in meta on Just a Blog in the Park</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href="https://github.com/Artiavis">Jeff Rabinowitz&lt;/a>, 2019</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.justabloginthepark.com/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Switching to Hugo Blogging</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2017/06/03/switching-to-hugo-blogging/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2017/06/03/switching-to-hugo-blogging/</guid><description>I recently decided to switch the backend static site compilation toolchain for this blog from the small Cryogen project in Clojure to the venerable Hugo project written in Golang. Although I had previously written that I wanted a hackable static site generator at Returning to Blogging with Cryogen, my requirements lately have changed. I thought I'd write a couple of quick notes about why I switched (and why I didn't).</description></item><item><title>Returning to Blogging with Cryogen</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2015/10/24/returning-to-blogging-with-cryogen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2015/10/24/returning-to-blogging-with-cryogen/</guid><description>It's been a long while since I last blogged. My last post dates back to April of 2014, shortly before I graduated from Rutgers Engineering. My life since then has been a bit of a whirlwind. I've since graduated, moved to the Upper West Side, started working in banking, gotten engaged and married, and moved out. I suppose I could be forgiven for not blogging as actively.
Why I Took Down My Old Blog My old blog was running on Ghost, a nifty JavaScript-based modern reimagination of the classic web-based blogging platform.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the Park!</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2013/10/28/welcome-to-the-park/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2013/10/28/welcome-to-the-park/</guid><description>I love going for walks in the park. Whether I'm flushed with ideas and want to let them percolate in my head, or I'm bone dry and can't seem to get a single thought to hit me, I find going for a walk always helps. Something about keeping moving and watching the world stroll by always seems to get the juices flowing at just the right pace.
But a walk can't be just anywhere to have this effect.</description></item></channel></rss>