<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dsp on Just a Blog in the Park</title>
    <link>http://justabloginthepark.com/tags/dsp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dsp on Just a Blog in the Park</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Artiavis&#34;&gt;Jeff Rabinowitz&lt;/a&gt;, 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://justabloginthepark.com/tags/dsp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitmap Graphics vs Vector Graphics</title>
      <link>http://justabloginthepark.com/2013/11/21/bitmap-graphics-vs-vector-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justabloginthepark.com/2013/11/21/bitmap-graphics-vs-vector-graphics/</guid>
      <description>One astute reader of a previous post observed that although I seemed to imply that only bitmaps can be digital images, there also exists such a thing as vector graphics which are also considered digital images. At the time, it was not clear in context what was meant in describing an image as digital. While I conflated digital images with bitmaps, which is inaccurate, I was only discussing bitmaps in that post, and the conclusions therein are still valid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Eigenfacebook</title>
      <link>http://justabloginthepark.com/2013/11/19/the-eigenfacebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justabloginthepark.com/2013/11/19/the-eigenfacebook/</guid>
      <description>The end of the fall semester is always a very special time of year. The hubbub of plans for winter break are omnipresent, festive lights illuminate themselves around campus, and most importantly of all, professors finally get around to assigning all their term projects with scarcely three weeks left with which to complete them. This isn&amp;rsquo;t news to my fellow upperclassmen, although the sophomores may only just begin to experience this for the first time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Smooth Out the Curves - Understanding Digital Image Filtering</title>
      <link>http://justabloginthepark.com/2013/11/04/how-to-smooth-out-the-curves-understanding-digital-image-filtering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justabloginthepark.com/2013/11/04/how-to-smooth-out-the-curves-understanding-digital-image-filtering/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I discussed the physical interpretation of digital music (and all digital audio) as both a time-varying signal and a frequency-varying signal. This, of course, makes intuitive sense - as we spend three or four minutes listening to a song, we can hear the guitars and horns coming in and fading out, a singer intone the chorus of a song, etc. At the same time, we appreciate the frequencies changing as well &amp;mdash; the singer hitting different notes, the instruments forming different chords.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Pump Up the Bass: Understanding Audio Frequencies</title>
      <link>http://justabloginthepark.com/2013/10/30/how-to-pump-up-the-bass-understanding-audio-frequencies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justabloginthepark.com/2013/10/30/how-to-pump-up-the-bass-understanding-audio-frequencies/</guid>
      <description>The other day I was having a discussion with my roommate Mike about the physical intuition of digital photographs, and how performing even the most fundamental of operations (e.g. resizing) requires an appreciation of the underlying mathematics. We are both currently in image processing classes, but very different kinds. His course is in Computer Science, so his studies tend to be of the use Java; things happen; make apps variety, with only some slight motivation and understanding of what&amp;rsquo;s happening under the hood.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>