<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Dsp on Just a Blog in the Park</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/tags/dsp/</link><description>Recent content in Dsp on Just a Blog in the Park</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href="https://github.com/Artiavis">Jeff Rabinowitz&lt;/a>, 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.justabloginthepark.com/tags/dsp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bitmap Graphics vs Vector Graphics</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2013/11/21/bitmap-graphics-vs-vector-graphics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2013/11/21/bitmap-graphics-vs-vector-graphics/</guid><description>&lt;p>One astute reader of
&lt;a href="https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2013/11/04/how-to-smooth-out-the-curves-understanding-digital-image-filtering/">a previous post&lt;/a> observed that
although I seemed to imply that only
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bitmap">bitmaps&lt;/a>
can be digital images, there also exists such a thing as
&lt;a href="//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vector_graphics">vector graphics&lt;/a>
which are also considered
digital images. At the time, it was not clear in context what was meant in
describing an image as &lt;em>digital&lt;/em>. While I conflated digital images with bitmaps,
which is inaccurate, I was only discussing bitmaps in that post, and the
conclusions therein are still valid.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Eigenfacebook</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2013/11/19/the-eigenfacebook/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2013/11/19/the-eigenfacebook/</guid><description>&lt;p>The end of the fall semester is always a very special time of year. The hubbub
of plans for winter break are omnipresent, festive lights illuminate themselves
around campus, and most importantly of all, professors finally get around to
assigning all their term projects with scarcely three weeks left with which to
complete them. This isn&amp;rsquo;t news to my fellow upperclassmen, although the
sophomores may only just begin to experience this for the first time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Smooth Out the Curves - Understanding Digital Image Filtering</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2013/11/04/how-to-smooth-out-the-curves-understanding-digital-image-filtering/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2013/11/04/how-to-smooth-out-the-curves-understanding-digital-image-filtering/</guid><description>&lt;p>In &lt;a href="https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2013/10/30/how-to-pump-up-the-bass-understanding-audio-frequencies/">a previous post&lt;/a>, I discussed the physical
interpretation of digital music (and all digital audio) as both a time-varying
signal and a frequency-varying signal. This, of course, makes intuitive sense -
as we spend three or four minutes listening to a song, we can hear the guitars
and horns coming in and fading out, a singer intone the chorus of a song, etc.
At the same time, we appreciate the frequencies changing as well — the
singer hitting different notes, the instruments forming different chords.
Understanding the time and frequency behavior of auditory information is fairly
intuitive - in fact, one could even argue that visualizing the frequency-based
content is more informative than visualizing the time-based content.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Pump Up the Bass: Understanding Audio Frequencies</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2013/10/30/how-to-pump-up-the-bass-understanding-audio-frequencies/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2013/10/30/how-to-pump-up-the-bass-understanding-audio-frequencies/</guid><description>&lt;p>The other day I was having a discussion with my roommate Mike about the physical
intuition of digital photographs, and how performing even the most fundamental
of operations (e.g. resizing) requires an appreciation of the underlying
mathematics. We are both currently in image processing classes, but very
different kinds. His course is in Computer Science, so his studies tend to be of
the &lt;em>&lt;strong>use Java; things happen; make apps&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> variety, with only some slight
motivation and understanding of what&amp;rsquo;s happening under the hood. My course, on
the other hand, is in Electrical Engineering, which means it is of the &lt;em>&lt;strong>here&amp;rsquo;s
some math, and here&amp;rsquo;s how you do this math in Matlab&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> variety. There&amp;rsquo;s
advantages to both educational approaches, but debating the merits of theory-
centric versus application-centric education styles is beyond the scope of this
post. Instead I want to quickly motivate some of the fundamental theorems of
Signal Processing and show how they are applied. In this post, I will cover the
first, and most intuitive, of signals: audio.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>