<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Just a Blog in the Park</title>
    <link>http://Artiavis.github.io/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on Just a Blog in the Park</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Artiavis&#34;&gt;Jeff Rabinowitz&lt;/a&gt;, 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://Artiavis.github.io/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Holiday in Italy</title>
      <link>http://Artiavis.github.io/2016/06/26/my-first-holiday-in-italy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://Artiavis.github.io/2016/06/26/my-first-holiday-in-italy/</guid>
      <description>This blog post is long overdue; I&amp;rsquo;ve been a bit preoccupied since getting back to the States, but I wanted to briefly share some of my thoughts from my recent honeymoon in Italy.
My wife and I had our long-overdue honeymoon early last month, in gorgeous Italy: Venice, Rome, Florence, and Milan. This was the realization of a dream for us; few countries in the world have the culture, history, art, dining, and exquisite beauty which Italy has.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Entry - Quick Border Reentry</title>
      <link>http://Artiavis.github.io/2014/01/23/global-entry---quick-border-reentry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://Artiavis.github.io/2014/01/23/global-entry---quick-border-reentry/</guid>
      <description>Last week, when I got back to JFK after my Israel trip, I was kind of dreading going through customs &amp;ndash; and not because I was carrying contraband. Last time I went through border control, I spent what felt like forty five minutes (after a twelve hour flight, no less) waiting to go to the bathroom and grab my luggage and scram. However, this time around, I saw something which piqued my interest, and somewhat reminded me of my earlier eigenface project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pathways Israel</title>
      <link>http://Artiavis.github.io/2014/01/17/pathways-israel/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://Artiavis.github.io/2014/01/17/pathways-israel/</guid>
      <description>Each winter at University, I find myself wondering what to do with my winter breaks about a week before finals. Usually I spend my breaks conducting research for various labs at Rutgers, or else getting a head-start on school for the Spring. So about this time last month, while wondering what I would do with my (hopefully) final winter break of undergraduate studies, I received an email which offered a fantastic opportunity &amp;mdash; go to Israel for two weeks on a deeply discounted program!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>