<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tiddlywiki on Just a Blog in the Park</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/tags/tiddlywiki/</link><description>Recent content in tiddlywiki on Just a Blog in the Park</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href="https://github.com/Artiavis">Jeff Rabinowitz&lt;/a>, 2023</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 20:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.justabloginthepark.com/tags/tiddlywiki/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Turning Over a New Writing Leaf</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2021/01/18/turning-over-a-new-writing-leaf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 20:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2021/01/18/turning-over-a-new-writing-leaf/</guid><description>Have you ever known that you wanted to write about something, but weren&amp;rsquo;t sure where to start? I&amp;rsquo;ve often experienced that when writing for this very blog. I&amp;rsquo;ll have a topic like programming or cooking that I want to share a thought about, and get stuck&amp;hellip; starting. That&amp;rsquo;s one of the reasons I haven&amp;rsquo;t been blogging as often as I&amp;rsquo;d have liked to.
In order to tackle this &amp;ldquo;writer&amp;rsquo;s block&amp;rdquo;, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try changing my blogging approach in three related ways: setting explicit writing goals, taking notes towards those ends, and not rushing the writing process.</description></item><item><title>Saving TiddlyWiki Documents</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2021/01/01/saving-tiddlywiki-documents/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 13:34:59 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2021/01/01/saving-tiddlywiki-documents/</guid><description>Using a TiddlyWiki is a tale of two cities:
Each TiddlyWiki document is a single HTML file that contains 100% of its own source code and data and is compatible with all modern browsers (and operating systems). Therefore, opening and reading a TiddlyWiki couldn&amp;rsquo;t be simpler. On the other hand, editing TiddlyWiki is a bit messy if done without a plugin. With a plugin, editing and saving a TiddlyWiki happens &amp;ldquo;in-place&amp;rdquo;, the same as with a Microsoft Word document (or the like).</description></item><item><title>Interesting TiddlyWiki Apps</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2020/12/31/interesting-tiddlywiki-apps/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2020/12/31/interesting-tiddlywiki-apps/</guid><description>I continue to be fascinated by the world of TiddlyWiki, and have been trying to scratch an itch in my mind by learning more about it. One of the deeper aspects of TiddlyWiki, called out by its creator Jeremy Ruston (https://jermolene.com/), is that TiddlyWiki can be leveraged by non-software-developers to craft ad-hoc, well-tailored informational &amp;ldquo;apps&amp;rdquo;. This is very similar to how non-software-developers have used Microsoft Excel&amp;rsquo;s spreadsheet-scripting to do likewise in business, crafting custom programs to meet a need, without paying for software developers to get into the mix.</description></item><item><title>Playing with Tiddlywiki</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2020/12/29/playing-with-tiddlywiki/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 08:05:04 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2020/12/29/playing-with-tiddlywiki/</guid><description>People who are close to me know that I have a bit of a thing for Productivity Software of all shapes and sizes. I&amp;rsquo;m usually a categorical thinker; I rely on notes (either my own or those others put up online) to acquire specialized knowledge in a variety of subjects, which I then bring to the table at work and at home. Therefore, I&amp;rsquo;ve had an on-again-off-again affair with various note-taking apps.</description></item></channel></rss>