<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Music on Just a Blog in the Park</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/tags/music/</link><description>Recent content in Music on Just a Blog in the Park</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href="https://github.com/Artiavis">Jeff Rabinowitz&lt;/a>, 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.justabloginthepark.com/tags/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Pump Up the Bass: Understanding Audio Frequencies</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2013/10/30/how-to-pump-up-the-bass-understanding-audio-frequencies/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2013/10/30/how-to-pump-up-the-bass-understanding-audio-frequencies/</guid><description>&lt;p>The other day I was having a discussion with my roommate Mike about the physical
intuition of digital photographs, and how performing even the most fundamental
of operations (e.g. resizing) requires an appreciation of the underlying
mathematics. We are both currently in image processing classes, but very
different kinds. His course is in Computer Science, so his studies tend to be of
the &lt;em>&lt;strong>use Java; things happen; make apps&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> variety, with only some slight
motivation and understanding of what&amp;rsquo;s happening under the hood. My course, on
the other hand, is in Electrical Engineering, which means it is of the &lt;em>&lt;strong>here&amp;rsquo;s
some math, and here&amp;rsquo;s how you do this math in Matlab&lt;/strong>&lt;/em> variety. There&amp;rsquo;s
advantages to both educational approaches, but debating the merits of theory-
centric versus application-centric education styles is beyond the scope of this
post. Instead I want to quickly motivate some of the fundamental theorems of
Signal Processing and show how they are applied. In this post, I will cover the
first, and most intuitive, of signals: audio.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>