<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Python on Just a Blog in the Park</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/tags/python/</link><description>Recent content in Python on Just a Blog in the Park</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href="https://github.com/Artiavis">Jeff Rabinowitz&lt;/a>, 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 22:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.justabloginthepark.com/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Recommended Programming Languages for High School Students</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2020/02/02/recommended-programming-languages-for-high-school-students/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 22:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2020/02/02/recommended-programming-languages-for-high-school-students/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;em>&lt;strong>Disclaimer&lt;/strong>: All opinions expressed herein are my own and don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily
reflect that of my employer.&lt;/em>
&lt;em>&lt;strong>Caveat&lt;/strong>: I hold these opinions and make these recommendations specifically
with respect to high school students (or casual hobbyists).&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have a friend in my neighborhood who teaches high school computer science.
When she happened to mention that she was trying a new curriculum for one of
her classes, I asked her which programming language she was planning to use
in her class. She said that she hadn&amp;rsquo;t quite decided yet, but was leaning
towards JavaScript, because it&amp;rsquo;s ubiquitous and (importantly!) runs well on her
school&amp;rsquo;s Chromebook machines.
Upon hearing that she was favoring JavaScript,
I ran my mouth and
recommend that she instead consider Python.
Based on my professional experience with both JavaScript and Python,
I feel comfortable stating that JavaScript has quite a few pitfalls in terms of
learning, and has a non-trivial path to writing high-quality code.
I also feel comfortable stating that Python has a number of educational virtues,
and has a fairly strong path for students to learn to write high-quality code.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Switching to Hugo Blogging</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2017/06/03/switching-to-hugo-blogging/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2017/06/03/switching-to-hugo-blogging/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently decided to switch the backend static site compilation toolchain for
this blog from the small &lt;a href="https://github.com/cryogen-project/cryogen">Cryogen project&lt;/a>
in &lt;a href="https://clojure.org/">Clojure&lt;/a> to the venerable &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo&lt;/a>
project written in &lt;a href="https://golang.org/">Golang&lt;/a>. Although I had previously
written that I wanted a hackable static site generator at
&lt;a href="https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2015/10/24/returning-to-blogging-with-cryogen/">Returning to Blogging with Cryogen&lt;/a>,
my requirements lately have changed.
I thought I&amp;rsquo;d write a couple of quick notes about why I switched (and why I didn&amp;rsquo;t).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="hackabletoolchain--maintainabletoolchain">hackableToolchain &amp;lt;&amp;lt; maintainableToolchain&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>An easily hackable blog generator became less valueable to me than a robust and well
maintained one. Although it was nice getting to contribute code to Cryogen and to
make a difference, and to be able to understand the code base, the value of established
and battle-tested code is something I ignored at the time. (I knew it was a factor,
but at the time I just wanted to get rolling quickly. These days I&amp;rsquo;d rather have
something that works on its own.)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Returning to Blogging with Cryogen</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2015/10/24/returning-to-blogging-with-cryogen/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2015/10/24/returning-to-blogging-with-cryogen/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a long while since I last blogged. My last post dates back to
April of 2014, shortly before I graduated from Rutgers Engineering.
My life since then has been a bit of a whirlwind. I&amp;rsquo;ve since graduated,
moved to the Upper West Side, started working in banking, gotten engaged
and married, and moved out. I suppose I could be forgiven for not blogging
as actively.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="why-i-took-down-my-old-blog">Why I Took Down My Old Blog&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My old blog was running on &lt;a href="ghost.org">Ghost&lt;/a>, a nifty JavaScript-based
modern reimagination of the classic web-based blogging platform. Ghost
has some gorgeous themes, a svelte editing experience, and seems poised
to be the next generation of blogging platforms. It seems great. Why
did I leave it behind?&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>