<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Video Games on Just a Blog in the Park</title>
    <link>http://justabloginthepark.com/tags/video-games/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Video Games on Just a Blog in the Park</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Artiavis&#34;&gt;Jeff Rabinowitz&lt;/a&gt;, 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 14:30:28 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://justabloginthepark.com/tags/video-games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Review: Overwatch</title>
      <link>http://justabloginthepark.com/2017/06/04/review-overwatch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 14:30:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justabloginthepark.com/2017/06/04/review-overwatch/</guid>
      <description>Around February, a friend told me that the extremely popular (and award-winning) &amp;ldquo;Overwatch&amp;rdquo; video game was on sale for Chinese New Years. It was available at something like half off, so I picked it up and decided to try it out. This is essentially my first purchase of a video game that could be considered an FPS, a shooter, and a &amp;ldquo;Team Fortress&amp;rdquo; style objective-based unique character-driven map. Here are my thoughts on it in brief.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XCOM2: Review</title>
      <link>http://justabloginthepark.com/2017/03/19/xcom2-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justabloginthepark.com/2017/03/19/xcom2-review/</guid>
      <description>Over the holidays I picked up the iPad version of XCOM: Enemy Within, the previous iteration in the XCOM franchise. For those unfamiliar with XCOM, it&amp;rsquo;s a brilliant (but extremely challenging) series of turn-based tiled-map strategy games. Although I ended up wiping close to 2&amp;frasl;3 of the way through my play through, I found Enemy Within compelling enough to try out XCOM 2, with some encouragement from friends and family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparing Freemium Game Models</title>
      <link>http://justabloginthepark.com/2016/01/10/comparing-freemium-game-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justabloginthepark.com/2016/01/10/comparing-freemium-game-models/</guid>
      <description>I suppose I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing freemium video games for a few years now. (For those who haven&amp;rsquo;t heard of the &amp;ldquo;freemium&amp;rdquo; business model, it&amp;rsquo;s the strategy of selling a good or service which is free to access but costs money for premium features. Freemium software, especially video games, are popular because the barrier to entry is made as low as possible to hook people. I highly recommend the South Park episode on the subject, &amp;ldquo;Freemium Isn&amp;rsquo;t Free&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>