<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cooking on Just a Blog in the Park</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/tags/cooking/</link><description>Recent content in cooking on Just a Blog in the Park</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href="https://github.com/Artiavis">Jeff Rabinowitz&lt;/a>, 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 19:37:52 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.justabloginthepark.com/tags/cooking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I Got an Instant Pot</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2021/06/27/i-got-an-instant-pot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 19:37:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2021/06/27/i-got-an-instant-pot/</guid><description>I Got an Instant Pot Last year, I picked up an Instant Pot multi cooker, thinking it would simplify cooking dinner on weeknights. Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve owned and used it for about 9 months, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share what I like about it, and what I don’t. For the record, I’m using the basic Instant Pot Duo 6-quart model.
Capabilities I Use The Instant Pot is sort of like a Dutch Oven — it’s a thick-bottomed steel pot that can sauté, steam, and pressure cook food.</description></item><item><title>Making chicken stock from scratch</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2018/04/09/making-chicken-stock-from-scratch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 19:07:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2018/04/09/making-chicken-stock-from-scratch/</guid><description>Yesterday, I woke up and decided to try and make chicken stock from scratch. And, after another ten minutes of reflection, I further resolved to make it &amp;ldquo;from scratch&amp;rdquo; if at all possible. I rushed out the door to go grocery shopping, and grabbed the first set of ingredients: soup greens. Then, while I was at the butcher, I grabbed the second set of ingredients: chicken bones (prepackaged). (The bones ran me about $5, but my butcher charges a lot because they&amp;rsquo;re the only game in town; I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure at other places it would be cheaper.</description></item><item><title>Review: Dini Delivers</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2018/03/17/review-dini-delivers/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 20:10:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2018/03/17/review-dini-delivers/</guid><description>Lately, both my wife and I have been working long hours at our jobs; the health of our diets have suffered as a result. Although we have a few minutes each night to cook, we don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to run out to the market in the middle of the week, or to lavish time on a full-course meal. Whereas in years past I used to dictate the meal plan for the week and put two or three complex dishes into each weeks&amp;rsquo; menu, that either my wife or I would simply make after arriving home from work, these days we scarcely even have time for that.</description></item><item><title>How Programming is Like Cooking</title><link>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2016/01/09/how-programming-is-like-cooking/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.justabloginthepark.com/2016/01/09/how-programming-is-like-cooking/</guid><description>Peter Naur, famous in the programming world for his contributions to ALGOL and the Backus-Naur Form (BNF) notation for expressing grammars, passed away last week. (For those who are not in the programming world, ALGOL&amp;rsquo;s grammatical syntax inspired most of today&amp;rsquo;s most popular programming languages, like C, C++, Java, and Python). As a very young millennial programmer, I&amp;rsquo;d of course heard Naur&amp;rsquo;s name from the BNF notation, but didn&amp;rsquo;t really get to appreciate just how prescient his work was at the time.</description></item></channel></rss>