<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Photography on Just a Blog in the Park</title>
    <link>http://justabloginthepark.com/tags/photography/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Photography on Just a Blog in the Park</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Artiavis&#34;&gt;Jeff Rabinowitz&lt;/a&gt;, 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 21:45:34 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://justabloginthepark.com/tags/photography/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuji TCL-X100 II</title>
      <link>http://justabloginthepark.com/2017/12/05/fuji-tcl-x100-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 21:45:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justabloginthepark.com/2017/12/05/fuji-tcl-x100-ii/</guid>
      <description>In addition to my aforementioned impulsive purchase of the Fujifilm Instax SP-2 smartphone printer (for printing mementos from social occasions), I also impulsively purchased the Fujifilm TCL-X100 II teleconversion lens for my Fujifilm X100T camera. This was something I was thinking about for a while about a week, and although I hesitated quite a bit in the store, I ended up pulling the trigger on it.
  The Fuji TCL-X100 II conveter lens is an engineering marvel, and when attached to the camera, looks quite convincingly part of the original body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fujifilm Instax SP-2: The Friendly Portable Photograph Printer</title>
      <link>http://justabloginthepark.com/2017/11/29/fujifilm-instax-sp-2-the-friendly-portable-photograph-printer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 11:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justabloginthepark.com/2017/11/29/fujifilm-instax-sp-2-the-friendly-portable-photograph-printer/</guid>
      <description>A little over a week ago, I went out and picked up the Fujifilm Instax SP-2(smartphone) printer from B&amp;amp;H to bring to a friend&amp;rsquo;s wedding. Though this was a bit of an impulse purchase, I had my eye on this printer for a couple of weeks, and thought I would get good use out of it going into Thanksgiving Weekend. It&amp;rsquo;s kind of like a Polaroid for the 21st century, except you know (more or less) what your pics will turn out like before printing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mpix Photo Prints</title>
      <link>http://justabloginthepark.com/2017/09/14/mpix-photo-prints/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 00:40:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justabloginthepark.com/2017/09/14/mpix-photo-prints/</guid>
      <description>As I recently discussed, I&amp;rsquo;ve recently acquired a camera for improving my family photography (and maybe also indulging in some hobbyist photography as well). My original motivation for purchasing that camera was not just to have better quality digital photos, but especially to have beautiful photos which I can frame or put into family albums.
Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve been shooting for a little while, I decided to order some prints online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuji X100T</title>
      <link>http://justabloginthepark.com/2017/08/13/fuji-x100t/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2017 21:43:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justabloginthepark.com/2017/08/13/fuji-x100t/</guid>
      <description>On July 4th, I jetted over to B&amp;amp;H to pick up a new(ly used) camera. I walked out with a Fujifilm X100T mirrorless point-and-shoot camera. This is the story of how I chose that camera, and how I feel about it a few weeks later.
It all begins&amp;hellip; with me staying up until 4 o&amp;rsquo;clock in the morning one Saturday night. What had begun as an innocent review of my family photos perversely devolved into a compulsive episode of researching cameras with which to upgrade said family photos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ACDsee for Photography</title>
      <link>http://justabloginthepark.com/2017/07/11/using-acdsee-for-photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2017 20:42:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justabloginthepark.com/2017/07/11/using-acdsee-for-photography/</guid>
      <description>For the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been interested in a more powerful digital photography workflow solution than the brutish practice of shuffling JPG files around on my hard drive and hoping for the best. I have really been seeking one (or more) specialized programs which can handle the common photography tasks of organizing photos from the moment they leave the camera to their final resting place on my hard drive (and/or backup server), and performing common photo editing upon them like curve adjustments and blemish removal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Impressed by iPhone Photography</title>
      <link>http://justabloginthepark.com/2016/06/26/im-impressed-by-iphone-photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justabloginthepark.com/2016/06/26/im-impressed-by-iphone-photography/</guid>
      <description>My wife and I got back from our honeymoon in Italy a few weeks ago (which you can read about here), and I need to remark on how impressed I am by the performance our iPhones. Both my wife&amp;rsquo;s iPhone 5S and my iPhone 6 performed spectacularly, taking hundreds of photos for us during our ten days on holiday.
I know there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of marketing hype about how good the iPhone camera is, but this was my first time relying exclusively upon a smartphone camera for pictures of a momentous chapter of my life, and I now buy the hype.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitmap Graphics vs Vector Graphics</title>
      <link>http://justabloginthepark.com/2013/11/21/bitmap-graphics-vs-vector-graphics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justabloginthepark.com/2013/11/21/bitmap-graphics-vs-vector-graphics/</guid>
      <description>One astute reader of a previous post observed that although I seemed to imply that only bitmaps can be digital images, there also exists such a thing as vector graphics which are also considered digital images. At the time, it was not clear in context what was meant in describing an image as digital. While I conflated digital images with bitmaps, which is inaccurate, I was only discussing bitmaps in that post, and the conclusions therein are still valid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Smooth Out the Curves - Understanding Digital Image Filtering</title>
      <link>http://justabloginthepark.com/2013/11/04/how-to-smooth-out-the-curves---understanding-digital-image-filtering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://justabloginthepark.com/2013/11/04/how-to-smooth-out-the-curves---understanding-digital-image-filtering/</guid>
      <description>In a previous post, I discussed the physical interpretation of digital music (and all digital audio) as both a time-varying signal and a frequency-varying signal. This, of course, makes intuitive sense - as we spend three or four minutes listening to a song, we can hear the guitars and horns coming in and fading out, a singer intone the chorus of a song, etc. At the same time, we appreciate the frequencies changing as well &amp;mdash; the singer hitting different notes, the instruments forming different chords.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>